What does the investment climate look like for unlisted companies?
And how do it go-
-Klar CEO Sebastian Siemiatkowski's investment company Flat Capital-
-which, among other things, invested in Open AI where it has been messy lately.
We will talk about that in today's EFN market.
Welcome.
-Welcome Hanna Wachtmeister.
-Thanks.
Fun to be here.
Fun to have you here.
You are CEO of the investment company Flat Capital.
Today we will talk about trends and the investment climate for mainly unlisted companies.
But also about flat capital, of course.
We start there.
What is Flat Capital for companies?
Flat Capital is listed since 2021. A small investment company-
-What is checked and owned mainly by Sebastian and Nina Siemiatkowski.
-It started ... -klar -founder and CEO.
Good.
You get stuck in who they are ...
Nina and Sebastian with their entrepreneurial travel were given the opportunity to invest-
-In other entrepreneurs around 2013, when Flat Capital saw their first light.
They began to invest in, among other things, budbee, or today Instabe, and Truecaller.
Can you tell us a little more about your strategy and why are you focusing on unlisted companies?
Our strategy has its basis very much in mainly Sebastian's experiences-
-When I was in.
Brief
-They we believe that an interesting return profile is-
-In the opportunity to be long -term.
Being a long -term investor in companies.
Because it takes time to build companies.
Not four years.
Klarna ... Sebastian has been holding on for 18 years.
And will last for another 18 years.
Building good companies takes time.
And do you have a fund structure that is common in the unlisted world-
-If the funds often have a lifetime, they are built up.
And there is a possible conflict in how you build companies and maximize value-
-Man between if you are a "venture capital"-investor-
But unfortunately in the unlisted world, or as it works in the unlisted world-
-So they are not noted on an active market-
-What they have their capital raising rounds when setting new values-
-What means that the values ...
They can change a lot, sometimes fast and sometimes not so fast.
So in the Klarna case we have invested the equivalent of 34 million, a little over.
But then they did a round last summer, when the holding was written down-
-In connection to a capital raising as they did.
And we have other examples of this list, type budbee or instabbee-
-Where invested capital is 7.5 million-
-But the company is valued significantly higher today after different rounds.
They do not want their values to be seen too much.
So these are these two scales all the time, that we are considering.
Today, how big is the premium on your net asset value?
14 % I have for me.
But there.
-And then it moves very much, of course.
-We looked at the course here ...
The last rise in November came after information that Klarna should be listed on the stock exchange.
If that happens, what would it mean for your investment in Klarna?
It is a good question, and something that we discuss on the board.
The principle question is ... We are very much associated with Klarna-
-In that Sebastian is the CEO and founder of Klarna.
And flat had not been found without clear, you can claim.
But it is probably about ... "Can we sit on a listed holding in our portfolio?"
And there we probably have to come back, I think.
But that is something that we can absolutely absolutely.
For example, we are still at a post in Truecaller, which is also a listed company.
But our business concept is based on being unlisted.
So I have to come back around it.
-The engagement of all employees, and how important it is.
So I think Sam and his team, based on what I've read ...
After all, it feels like he's really "committed" to run this now.
So it feels safe anyway.
Although it has been nervous.
How did you reason when you chose to invest in the company?
We think AI is an inevitable-
-And very exciting and quite scary type of trend, or what to call it.
It is not a sector, but an element that all companies need to take a stand for
-and integrate.
And it's so big and it goes so fast-
-It is clear that we find it exciting.
Then we reason so that it is probably very easy to go wrong and invest wrong.
The values have dropped.
The important thing is to ensure that you invest in companies that continue to grow-
-So they are not in a giant lame spiral.
Because then maybe "cheap" at multiple level is really very expensive.
So you have to be careful when saying: "Oh, what cheap it looks."
You have to keep your tongue in your mouth, or what you say.
And finally, what are you looking for?
What trends do you look forward?
Where are you looking?
We have had quite interesting discussions.
We really have, especially with Sebastian, but also in the board-
-The insights in large companies and what they take a stand now and what they see ...
We have a great spect of AI and the value risk that comes with it.